Guide to the Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs ARC.306
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 2: Everett H. Ortner personal papers, 1873, circa 1932-2007
  Sub-series 2.3: Popular Science
  Sub-series 2.4: Ortner family and genealogy
  - Sub-series 2.1: EHO school and childhood papers, circa 1932-2006; 5.7 Linear Feet in eight folders, two flat boxes, and one small box
    The sub-series documents EHO's childhood and his education at James Madison High School, Jamaica High School, and the University of Arkansas, dating from circa 1932 to 2006. It contains yearbooks, course work, ephemera, correspondence, and memorabilia. It includes one letter from Bill Clinton congratulating the 2006 Distinguished Alumni of J. William Fulbright College of Arts and Sciences (University of Arkansas).
    - EHO bar mitzvah speech and school memorabilia, circa 1932-1938 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Includes college photographic identification booklets
    - EHO elementary school completion certificate, 1931 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - Jamaica High School Senior Yearbook, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - EHO college papers, circa 1936-1939 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - University of Arkansas correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - University of Arkansas Razorback (two yearbooks), 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - University of Arkansas diploma, 1939 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - James Madison High School - Class of 1935 - 60th reunion, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - James Madison High School - Class of 1935 - 60th reunion tote bag, 1995 (Box 77, Folder -)
    - University of Arkansas, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes letter from Bill Clinton
    - J. William Fulbright College of Arts and Sciences Distinguished Alumnus award statue (University of Arkansas), 2006 (Box 70, Item -)
  - Sub-series 2.2: Army, 1941-2003; 4.6 Linear Feet in nine folders, three oversize folders, and one small box
    The sub-series documents EHO's career in the United States Army, including his training at Fort Benning, service in World War II, his time as a prisoner of war in Germany, and his post-war service. It includes Army memoranda and special orders, reports, publications, correspondence (both military and personal), photographs, financial records, certificates, memorabilia (including his Bronze Star Medal), and ephemera, dating from 1941 to 2003. It also includes a report on his war experience written by a student.
    - Army - World War 2 mementos, 1940s (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Includes Army patches, dog tags, and European coins and paper money
    - Army - World War 2, 1941-1945 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - OCS 216, Fort Benning, Georgia group photograph and EHO cropped image, 1943, circa 2000s (Box 75, Folder -)
    - Army records, 1943-1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Army - POW mementos, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Includes EHO's identification card, messages to family, postcards, menus from S.S. Argentina, and a photograph of a woman
    - Army - Claims, POW stuff, and GI schooling, 1942-1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bronze Star Medal certificate, 1948 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Bronze Star Medal, service ribbon pin, and leather case, circa 1948 (Box 69, Item -)
      Possibly a replacement medal from circa 1970s-2000s
    - Army - Post-war, 1956-2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Includes photograph of EHO at Fort Devens, Massachusetts (1960)
    - Army promotions, 1960-1984 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Retirement Dinner in Honor of Colonel Leonard T. Scully, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Includes poem by EHO
    - Lucky Strike and Army - "My Stamp Album" - EHO WWII, 2000s (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Everett Ortner's World War Two Experiences" by Samantha Lindenauer, circa 2003 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 2.3: Popular Science, 1873, 1959-1983; 0.3 Linear Feet in ten folders
    The sub-series contains material relating to EHO's career as an editor and writer for Popular Science. It includes typescripts, photographs, correspondence, research files, clippings, and magazines, primarily dating from 1959 to 1983. It also includes an issue of The Popular Science Monthly from February 1873.
    Appraisal
    - The Popular Science Monthly, 1873 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Chamonix with EGO, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Contains letter, corrected typescript of articles, and photographs
    - Popular Science test car photographs, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Philippines Department of Trade - Photographs of EHO meeting, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Popular Science article on St. Peter's tomb - Typescripts and research, 1961-1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Includes photographs and programs for the dedication of the Apostolic Faith Mission (265 Lafayette Avenue, Brooklyn)
    - Popular Science "Any Dope Could Drive a Model T" by EHO clippings and negative, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Popular Science - Wernher von Braun typescript, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Popular Science note, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Popular Science magazines, 1980, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Popular Science spring poetry contest, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sub-series 2.4: Ortner family and genealogy, 1953-2007; 0.2 Linear Feet in five folders
    The sub-series contains files relating to EHO's family, especially his mother, Anna E. Ortner. It includes genealogical records, ephemera, and correspondence, dating from 1953 to 2007.
    - Poem from EHO to mother, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Ortner genealogy, 1994-2007 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Anne E. Ortner (EHO's mother), 1963-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Includes passport, death certificate, obituary, 1964 Worlds Fair tickets, The Green Point Savings Bank ephemera, and condolences
    - Harry Buegelesisen (EHO's uncle), 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Includes last will and testament
    - Sherry Ortner, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Everett and Evelyn Ortner personal papers, 1900-2012
  The series documents the professional, social, and familial lives of the Ortners, dating from 1900 to 2012. It includes an assortment of correspondence, clippings, photographs, ephemera, memorabilia, digital files, and other materials. The Ortners' involvement in Brooklyn cultural affairs and the historic preservation movement are well represented throughout the series.
  The series is organized into eight sub-series:
  Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs
  Sub-series 3.2: Personal correspondence
  Sub-series 3.3: Publicity
  Sub-series 3.4: 272 Berkeley Place
  Sub-series 3.5: Finances
  Sub-series 3.6: Address books
  Sub-series 3.7: Daily diaries
  Sub-series 3.8: Desktop computer tower
  - Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs, 1900-2010; 14.82 Linear Feet in six manuscript boxes, five flat boxes, two small boxes, and one oversize folder
    The sub-series contains a variety of materials that document the professional, social, and familial lives of the Ortners, dating from 1900 to 2010. It includes correspondence, photographs, clippings, writings, ephemera, and memorabilia. The Ortners' roles in Brooklyn's cultural institutions and the historic preservation movement are well represented throughout the sub-series.
    - E + E memorabilia - Mostly Everett, 1900-2006 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs (dating back to 1900), clippings, and ephemera
    - E + E pictures, 1915-2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Includes photographs of the Ortners and family, interior and exterior photographs of 272 Berkeley Place, family correspondence, and ephemera
    - E + E memorabilia, 1915-2008 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Includes portrait of EHO's mother, Brownstone Revival Committee, Develop Don't Destroy Brooklyn, Popular Science, EHO's writings, correspondence, clippings, and ephemera
    - EHO photographs, 1920s-2004 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - EGO photographs, circa 1920s-2000s (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - E + E memorabilia, 1939-2010 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Includes Brownstone Revival Committee/Coalition, photographs, clippings, and ephemera
    - Love letters and cards, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - EGO snapshots and photographs, circa 1940s-1986 (Box 53, Folder -)
      Includes photographs of EGO, EHO, friends, parties, special events, pets, Prospect Park, Fulton Ferry/Brooklyn Bridge, and foreign travel. Polaroid photographs have been removed and filed separately for preservation purposes.
    - Assorted memorabilia, 1940s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Includes EHO Army portrait, EGO identification cards, EHO business card, and travel ephemera
    - E + E memorabilia, 1940s-2009 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs, Army portrait of EHO, interior photographs of 272 Berkeley Place, Brownstone Revival Committee, Back to the City, course on Brownstones taught by EHO at the New School, clippings, and ephemera
    - Miscellaneous memories - OP/LP, 1941-2005 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Includes color transparencies of the interior of 116 Remsen Street (1963), photographs of EHO in the bath tub, a book titled Radio Talks on Mathematics (owned by EGO), a list of the Ortners' travels, correspondence, and clippings
    - E + E memorabilia, 1950-2009 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs, poems, Popular Science, correspondence, clippings, and ephemera
    - Wedding invitations, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - E + E memorabilia, 1953, 1993-2008 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs, clippings, and EGO memorials
    - E + E memorabilia (2 folders), 1959-1976 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
      Includes portraits of EGO, correspondence, clippings, and ephemera. Covers interior design, brownstones, Brooklyn Union Gas Company, Popular Science, and Long Island Historical Society.
    - Anne E. Ortner and dog photographs, 1960s (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Greece photographs, circa 1960s (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - EHO portrait, circa 1960s (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Unidentified Polaroids, circa 1960s (Box 68, Folder -)
    - Contact sheets, 1968 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - EGO resumes, 1960s-2000s (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - EGO business cards and driver's license, 1960s-2002 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - EGO early career photographs at 272 Berkeley Place, 1961-1971 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Includes resume, clippings, and Park Slope walking tour flyer
    - E + E odds and ends, 1961-2004 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Includes clippings, ephemera, a photograph of EGO, and invitation to the 100th anniversary of 272 Berkeley Place, and a note from Brooklyn Borough President Marty Markowitz
    - Puerto Rico vacation medium format color negatives, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Man with dogs photograph, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Victorian Society in America, 1966-1970, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Pet dog "Mara" and cat, 1966-1991 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Includes dog licenses, name plate, and letter regarding dog biting a neighbor
    - E + E memorabilia, 1966-2006 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Includes photographs, Brooklyn Brownstone Conference, 1992 Brownstone calendar, clippings, and ephemera
    - Contact sheet: various objects, 1968 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Mounted photograph #52: Young EHO sitting for a caricature, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Mounted photograph #54, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Oversize photographic prints, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 76, Folder -)
      Includes duplicate of mounted photograph #54
    - EHO portraits and biographical statements, 1970s-1980s (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Includes photographic prints and negatives
    - Dining with E + E, 1970s-2006 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - EGO odds and ends, 1970s-2006 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - A Centennial Celebration - Tolstoy's 'War and Peace' read in its entirety poster (WBAI 99.5), 1970 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
      In Oversize Posters folder
    - EGO Polaroid snapshots, circa 1970 (Box 68, Folder -)
    - EGO tribute file, 1970-2007 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      Includes obituaries, honors, photographs, clippings, mementos, and remembrances
    - EGO at Fulton Ferry Landing photograph by Jim Kallet, circa 1975 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - EGO - Art Commission and Landmarks Comission applications, 1976-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - E + E memorabilia, 1976-2010 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Includes photographs, Preservation Volunteers, Brownstone Revival Committee, Back to the City Conference, an interior design article by EGO, correspondence, clippings, and ephemera
    - EHO portraits - Matted Polaroids (three folders), 1977 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - EGO personal miscellaneous, 1977-2003 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Includes draft of speech delivered at Friends of BAM annual meeting and Long Island Historical Society Women's Committee files
    - Montauk Club, 1977, 2003-2004 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Old/Classic photographs, 1979-1990 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Assorted Honors, 1979-2005 (Box 72, Folder -)
      Oversize certificates from Brownstone Revivial Committee (BRC), Victorian Society in America, City of Louisville, and the Preservation League of New York State
    - 8"x8" computer diskettes, 1980s (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - EHO face pasted on historic preservation cartoon, circa 1980s (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - EHO, Howard Golden, and others photograph, circa 1980s (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Overseas Press Club, 1981-1983 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Ronald Reagan letter to EGO, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Award certificates, 1983-2002 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Includes Long Island Historical Society, Brooklyn Historical Society, and Historic Districts Council
    - Brooklyn Borough President citations honoring EGO and EHO, 1983, 1995, 2006 (Box 73, Folder -)
    - Mauela at City Hall negatives and contact sheets, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Savables, 1984-2009 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Includes clippings and correspondence
    - Who's Who - Biographical, 1984-2009 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Montauk Club stained glass dedication, 272 Berkeley Place parlor, EHO self-portraits, EGO portraits, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Negatives and contact sheets
    - 272 Berkeley Place 100th anniversary party photographs, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Park Slope Civic Council George Lougren Memorial Award - EHO, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn Brewery, 1987-2004 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - EGO with statuary Polaroids, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 68, Folder -)
    - Postcards, 1980-2000s (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Includes images of Brooklyn Botanic Graden and the Montauk Club taken by EHO, cards featuring EGO, Municipal Art Society postcards (including an image of 226 Berkeley Place), and historic images of Brooklyn
    - Bill Clinton inauguration and election night party invitations, 1992-1993 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Mayor David Dinkins - New-York Historical Society, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - St. Mary's Community Services - Preserving Community Art Award to EGO plaque, 1995 (Box 74, Item -)
    - Park Slope Civic Council Volunteer Award - EGO, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Ortner caricatures by Sam Norkin, 1996 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - "House of Ortner" dinner menus and hummus certificate, 1997-2005 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Eggenhofer art sale, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - E + E memorabilia, 1999-2008 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Includes Ortner party ephemera and photographs
    - Documents, 2000-2010 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence, EHO biographical statement, EHO talk on Park Slope, statement on EHO by EGO, statements on the Berkeley Carroll plan, and poem
    - Postal cards, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - E + E anniversary dinners, 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Awards, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Preservation League of New York State award, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Clippings and ephemera, 2004-2010 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      Includes correspondence, event invitations and programs, and photographs of an Ortner party
    - EHO birthday poem, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - BAM - EGO memorial service, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Lucy G. Moses Award, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Lucy G. Moses award statue, 2006 (Box 71, Item -)
    - EGO memorials and EHO letter to New York Times, 2006-2007 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - EHO curriculum vitae and award correspondence, 2006-2009 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Evelyn Ortner Memorial Day proclamation, 2007 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - EGO memorabilia, 2009-2010 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - EHO oral history interview, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      Recorded in 2003
    - Miscellaneous, 1871, 1960-2000s (Box 19, Folder 24)
      Includes proposal for a photographic survey of historic buildings, 1871 Report of the City Clerk of the City of Brooklyn (pages 350-351), poem by EHO (1960), 12th Street preschool negatives, and ephemera
  - Sub-series 3.2: Personal correspondence, 1939-2010; 1.2 Linear Feet in seventeen folders
    The sub-series primarily consists of letters and cards written by the Ortners' friends and family, dating from 1939 to 2010. It also includes a small amount of clippings and ephemera, as well some outgoing correspondence written. Some notable correspondents include as President Jimmy Carter, President Bill Clinton, Mayor John V. Lindsay, State Senator William T. Conklin, and Borough President Sebastian Leone. Items of note include the Ortners' love letters and a draft letter to the Brooklyn Union Gas Company regarding the Cinderalla project.
    Correspondence relating to brownstones and historic preservation can be found in Series 10: Brownstone correspondence.
    - Ortner family correspondence, 1939-1964 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Special correspondence (letters), 1951-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes President Jimmy Carter, President Bill Clinton, and draft letter to Brooklyn Union Gas Company regarding Cinderella Award
    - Special correspondence (cards) (3 folders), 1951-1993 (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
    - Special correspondence (ephemera), 1951-1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - E + E correspondence (3 folders), 1953-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
      Includes New York City Mayor John V. Lindsay, New York State Senator William T. Conklin, Brooklyn Borough President Sebastian Leone, and love letters from EHO to EGO
    - Sympathy cards for EGO's parents, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - EGO cards, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - EHO complaint letters, 1990-2004 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1995-2005 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (2 folders), 1999-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
    - EHO letters to New York Times, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - EHO e-mails, 2009-2010 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 3.3: Publicity, 1969-2004; 0.75 Linear Feet in nine folders
    The sub-series contains ephemera, clippings, correspondence, and clippings related to the Ortners' role in Brooklyn cultural organizations and the historic preservation movement, dating from 1969 to 2004. Major institutions represented in the sub-series include the Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM), Brooklyn Museum, Long Island Historical Society, Back to the City Conference, Montauk Club, and Brownstone Revival Committee. EGO's career as an interior designer is also represented in the sub-series.
    - E + E publicity (2 folders), 1969-1979 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
      Includes photographs, U.S. Congressman Fred Richmond, BAM, Brooklyn Museum, Long Island Historical Society, other cultural institutions, historic preservation, and interior design
    - EGO personal publicity (2 folders), 1970s (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
      Includes photographs, ephemera, correspondence, and clippings. Covers cultural institutions (especially BAM), historic preservation, and interior design.
    - Publicity - Lectures and clippings, 1974-2004 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - EHO publicity, 1976-1980s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - E + E publicity (2 folders), 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
      Includes photographs, historic preservation, interior design, Back to the City, Montauk Club, Brooklyn Union Gas Company, Long Island Historical Society, New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry, and U.S. Congressman Fred Richmond
    - EGO publicity, 1979-1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series 3.4: 272 Berkeley Place, circa 1905-2009; 1954-2009; 2 Linear Feet in ten folders and one flat box
    The sub-series consists of files material related to the Ortner's home at 272 Berkeley Place in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn. It includes photographs, mortgages, a guest book, and other files, dating from circa 1905 to 2009. It also includes material related to Elsie Hincken, the first owner of the building. Additional photographs and other files related to the building can be found in Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs, Series 4: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation photographs, and Series 12: Historic District Designation Reports.
    Generally arranged chronologically.
    - Copy of On Liberty by John Stuart Mill owned by Elsie Hincken, circa 1905 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Guest book, 1954-1986 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - 272 Berkeley Place interior photograph?, circa 1960s (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Williamsburgh Savings Bank - Mortgage, 1963-1978 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 272 Berkeley Place directions, circa 1968 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - 272 Berkeley Place burglaries, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs and slides
    - Studio apartment advertisement, circa 1990s (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Bluestone sidewalks, 1993-1995 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - 272 Berkeley Place notes, 2000s (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - 272 Berkeley Place interior photographs by Madeleine Isom, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - 272 Berkeley Place interior photographs by Levi Stolove, circa 2006 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Elsie Hincken - First owner of 272 Berkeley Place - Notes by EHO, 2007-2008 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Sub-series 3.5: Finances, 1963-2008; 0.25 Linear Feet in three folders
    The sub-series consist of the Ortners' expense journals and income tax returns, dating from 1963 to 2008.
    - Expense journals (three volumes), 1963-2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Income tax returns (two folders), 1996-2008 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
  - Sub-series 3.6: Address books, circa 1960s-2000s; 0.1 Linear Feet in one folder
    The sub-series contains the Ortner's address books, dating from circa 1960s to 2000s.
    - Address books, circa 1960s-2000s (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 3.7: Daily diaries, 1968-2009; 0.9 Linear Feet in three folders and one small box
    The sub-series consists of daily diaries that track the day-to-day affairs of the Ortners, dating from 1968 to 2009.
    - Daily diaries and notes, 1968, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Daily diaries (2 folders), 1981-1985 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Daily diaries (36 diaries), 1985-2009 (Box 15, Folder -)
  - Sub-series 3.8: Personal computer, 2000s-2012; 1.16 Linear Feet in one personal computer
    Conditions Governing Access
    This computer is currently unprocessed and unavailable to researchers.
    The collection includes one personal computer that belonged to the Ortners from the 2000s to 2012.
    - Personal computer, 2000s-2012 (Item Personal computer (1 of 1), Item -)
- Series 4: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation photographs, circa 1880s-2002
  The series contains photographs related to Brooklyn and historic preservation in a variety of formats, dating from circa 1880s to 2002. Formats include prints, slides, negatives, and glass plate negatives. The series includes original photograghs by EHO, copy photographs of historic images used by EHO in lectures, and a small amount of original photographs taken by other photographers.
  Additional photographs taken by the Ortners can be found in Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs.
  The series is organized into three sub-series:
  Sub-series 4.1: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation prints and negatives
  Sub-series 4.2: Brooklyn, Historic Preservation, and personal negatives
  Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides